const e="english",o=200,s=61,t=[{id:1613,question:"At the end of term in Forcados High School. Nene was saddled with the responsibility of",option:{a:"leading her house in the race",b:" packaging the gifts for presentation",c:"arranging the school hall for dinner",d:"organizing the carol night"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:1,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1614,question:"Efua was not in the good books of teachers at Forcados High School because",option:{a:"the students of Forcados did not like her",b:"she was expelled from her previous school",c:"she bribed the principal before she was admitted",d:"her admission into senior class was unusual"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:2,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1615,question:"In the novel, Ansa looked around glumly when Jimi was engrossed in laughter and chatter because he was",option:{a:"neglected by Jimi",b:"anxious to go home",c:"distracted by a band playing on the field",d:"given twelve strokes of the cane by the principal"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:3,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1616,question:"Mama Shilifat had an affection for Jimi because she always gave him",option:{a:"money to buy chewing gum",b:"advice against bad students",c:"the courage to do well in his class",d:" the largest pieces of puff-puff"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:4,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1617,question:`Ansa licked his lips and said furtively, look this is between you and me. Jimi would be angry if i told you but his brother is ---- well, we suspect he sometimes sells drugs and...'

From the excerpt above, Ansa was talking to`,option:{a:"Risikat and Nene",b:"Novi",c:"Caro",d:"Efua and Nene"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:5,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1618,question:"The speculation amongst the students of Forcados High School was that Jimi was dating",option:{a:"Risikat",b:"Joke",c:"Caro",d:"Efua"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:6,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1619,question:"Mr Solade sent Jimi to Ibadan for the holidays in order to",option:{a:"save Jimi from Wole's bad influence",b:"heed Jimi's request to stay with his friends",c:"allow Jimi spend some time with his friends",d:" allow Jimi to know more about Ibadan"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:7,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1620,question:"Students refused to sympathize with Efua when drinks spilled on her because",option:{a:"she would not accept their sympathy",b:" she was Jimi's only girlfriend",c:"they planned it to disgrace her",d:"they felt she was arrogant"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:8,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1621,question:"Which of the following best describes Mr Mallum?",option:{a:"He was a fat, tall man with wimpish behaviour",b:"He was a tall, wiry man with good diction",c:"He was crude, rash and impatient",d:"He was a small, wiry man with odd accent"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:9,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1622,question:"According to the novel, Efua was in Forcados High School because",option:{a:" her stepfather was a board member",b:" of her former principal's recommendation",c:" the school needed her mother's support",d:"of aunt Moni's gift to the school"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:10,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1623,question:`Jimi and Efua, there's something fishy going on there....
From the exercept above, the expression...something fishy refers to`,option:{a:"Nene's fear that Efua and Jimi were no longer going out",b:"Nene's fear that Jimi was not determined to jilt Efua",c:" Nene's annoyance that Efua might snatch Jimi from her",d:"Nene's suspicion that Jimi and Efua were having a relationship"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:11,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1624,question:"Seyi Lawal, the head boy of the school was described as someone who",option:{a:"loved his job",b:"hated Physics practical",c:"loved interacting with girls",d:"hated hard-work"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:12,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1625,question:"The author uses the novel to portray some of the",option:{a:" NGO's activities only",b:" environment conditions",c:" feelings of teachers only",d:" societal problems"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:13,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1626,question:"Efua's guarded and hostile attitude towards boys could be traced to",option:{a:" the teachings she had from her cleric",b:"stories she had heard from her aunt",c:" the experience she had with her stepfather",d:"her innate sense of justice"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:14,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1627,question:"Jimi was very prominent in Forcados High School because he was",option:{a:"the son of a great scholar",b:"the only child of his parents",c:"one of the school prefects",d:"noted for his good paintings"},section:"<b>These questions are based on A.H. Mohammed's The Last Days at Forcados High School.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:15,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1628,question:"Mr. Rufus bore the brunt in the last promotion examination.",option:{a:"Mr Rufus failed the examination woefully",b:"Mr Rufus excelled in the examination",c:"Mr. Rufus was excited about the examination",d:" Mr. Rufus toyed with the examination"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"bore the brunt; To suffer the worst part of an unpleasant or problematic situation.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:16,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1629,question:"My friend is well off nowadays",option:{a:"My friend is financially sound",b:"My friend is well known to people",c:"My fiend is now well",d:"My friend has lost focus"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"well off; wealthy. (in a favourable situation or circumstances).",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:17,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1630,question:"The retired army officer did a yeoman's service to the nation",option:{a:"His activity brought disrepute to the nation",b:" His service to the nation was not exemplary",c:"He was showered with the responsibilty of the yeoman",d:" He was very loyal to the nation"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"yeoman service; exceptionally good, useful, or loyal service or assistance. ",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:18,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1631,question:"He suddenly found himself in the thick of the situation",option:{a:"He did not agree with the situation",b:"He used his experience to settle the sitution",c:"He saved himself out of the situation",d:"He found himself deeply involved in the situation"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"be in the thick of something means = to be very involved at the busiest or most active stage of a situation or activity",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:19,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1632,question:"Olu and Ado are about to come to blows.",option:{a:"They are about to agree with each other",b:"They are about to accept other people's opinion",c:"They are about to hit each other",d:"They are about to disagree with other people's"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"come to blows; start fighting after a disagreement.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:20,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1633,question:"By refusing the offer, he has just cut down his own throat",option:{a:"He has made a big mistake",b:"He has made the right decision",c:"He has given up on his idea",d:" He has used the Knife on his throat"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"what is cut your own throat: to behave in a way that will cause harm ",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:21,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1634,question:"These job cuts are just the thin end of the wedge",option:{a:"Job cuts are very rampant",b:"Job cuts are the inconclusive",c:"Job cuts are the beginning of unpleasant situations",d:"Job cuts are the beginning of healthy rivalries"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"the thin end of the wedge : the beginning of a harmful development: ",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:22,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1635,question:"Jumai will do well if she was given a fair crack of the whip.",option:{a:"She would do well if she was given a fair whip",b:"She would excel if she used the whip well",c:"She would do well if she was given equal opportunity",d:"She would do well if she was made to cry"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"a fair crack of the whip : an equal chance to do something:",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:23,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1636,question:"Her death was a bolt from the blue to us ",option:{a:"Her death bolted us together",b:" Her death caused confusion",c:"Her death sealed our hopes",d:"Her death was unexpected"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"a bolt from the blue; a sudden and unexpected event.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:24,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1637,question:"The students were nosing around.",option:{a:"They were roaming about",b:"They were searching for information",c:" They were playing around",d:"They were disseminating information"},section:"For this question, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the question.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`Nose around/about something means to try to find out information about someone or something. 

Example: A few kids were nosing around.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:25,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1638,question:"It is important not to let mistakes <i>blight</i>  your life",option:{a:"damage",b:"impart",c:"improve",d:"ruin"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`<i>blight</i>; have a severely detrimental effect on. (a thing that spoils or damages something.)
improve; having become or been made better.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:26,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1639,question:"The film was shot in <i>decrepit</i> police station.",option:{a:"an improved",b:" a damaged",c:"an impoverished",d:"a dilapidated"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`<i>decrepit</i>  ; worn out or ruined because of age or neglect.
improved; having become or been made better.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:27,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1640,question:"Jumoke is fond of <i>carping</i> her sister",option:{a:"praising",b:"joking with",c:" complaining about",d:"faulting"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`<i>carping</i>; difficult to please; critical.
praising; express warm approval or admiration of.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:28,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1641,question:"A cup of coffee <i>invigorated</i> him",option:{a:"destroyed",b:"energized",c:"angered",d:"debilitated"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"d",solution:`<i>invigorated</i>  ; give strength or energy to.
debilitated; in a very weakened and infirm state.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:29,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1642,question:"It is <i>Iudicrous</i> to suggest that she was a government agent",option:{a:"odd",b:"exciting",c:"farcical",d:"sensible"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"d",solution:`<i>Iudicrous</i> ; so foolish, unreasonable, or out of place as to be amusing.
sensible; done or chosen in accordance with wisdom or prudence; likely to be of benefit.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:30,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1643,question:"The idea makes me <i>cringe</i>",option:{a:"quiver",b:"tremble",c:"resolute",d:"writhe"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`<i>cringe</i>; bend one's head and body in fear or apprehension or in a servile manner.
synonyms; shake, tremble, quiver, quail, quake
resolute; admirably purposeful, determined, and unwavering.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:31,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1644,question:"His book was one of those that <i>galvanized</i> democracy",option:{a:"stimulated",b:"encouraged",c:"dissauded",d:"promoted"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`<i>galvanized</i> ; shock or excite (someone) into taking action. 
synonyms;  excite, rouse, arouse, awaken, invigorate, fire, fuel, 

dissuade; persuade (someone) not to take a particular course of action.
synonyms; discourage, deter, prevent,`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:32,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1645,question:"He walks in a <i>gawky</i> way",option:{a:"suitable",b:"clumsy",c:"lumbering",d:"graceful"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"d",solution:`<i>gawky</i>; nervously awkward and ungainly.

graceful; having or showing grace or elegance`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:33,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1646,question:"The nation is in a period of economic <i>flux</i>",option:{a:"modification",b:"change",c:"fluidity",d:"stability"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"d",solution:`<i>flux</i>; the action or process of flowing or flowing out.

stability: the condition of being steady and not changing`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:34,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1647,question:"Our son was highly active and <i>exuberant</i>",option:{a:"subdued",b:"fulsome",c:"lively",d:"bright"},section:"For this question, choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`<i>exuberant</i>; full of energy, excitement, and cheerfulness.

subdued;  (of a person or their manner) quiet and rather reflective or depressed.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:35,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1648,question:`

Mr. Ojo has a <i>fickle</i> character.`,option:{a:"a genuine",b:" a stable",c:"an imperfect",d:"an unpredictable"},section:"For this question, choose the option nearest in meaning to the word or phrase in italics",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"<i>fickle</i>; changing frequently, especially as regards one's loyalties or affections.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:36,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1649,question:"Bola takes......his father both in appearance and his manner",option:{a:"On",b:"from",c:"after",d:"upon"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Bola takes after his father both in appearance and his manner",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:37,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1650,question:".........rich has its own problem",option:{a:"Being",b:"Been",c:"On being",d:"On been"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Being rich has its own problem.

Being; present participle of be.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:38,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1651,question:"The doctor listened to my heartbeat with a .........",option:{a:"cardiograph",b:"stethoscope",c:"chromometer",d:"microscope"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"stethoscope; a medical instrument for listening to the action of someone's heart or breathing, typically having a small disc-shaped resonator that is placed against the chest, and two tubes connected to earpieces.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:39,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1652,question:"With strong determination, Adamu was able to .... the problem",option:{a:"surmount",b:"surpass",c:"defend",d:"know"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`With strong determination, Adamu was able to surmount the problem

surmount means to overcome (a difficulty or obstacle).`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:40,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1653,question:"It is impossible to say whether ......Ola and her sister will be offered jobs by the firm.",option:{a:"both",b:"either",c:"each",d:"neither"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`It is impossible to say whether both Ola and her sister will be offered jobs by the firm.

Both is used for emphasis to refer to two people or things, regarded and identified together.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:41,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1654,question:"He decided to wait for the bus because he had..........",option:{a:"many luggages",b:"plenty luggages",c:"a lot of luggage",d:" too many luggage"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`He decided to wait for the bus because he had a lot of luggage

The noun luggage can be countable or uncountable. In more general, commonly used, contexts, the plural form will also beluggage. `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:42,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1655,question:"......lawyers enrolled at the Nigerian Bar last year....this year.",option:{a:"Very many/than",b:"Same/as",c:"More/than",d:"As/ much"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"more lawyers enrolled at the Nigerian Bar last year than this year.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:43,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1656,question:"The officer ....that he was not supposed to talk to the press on the matter",option:{a:"could have known",b:"shall know",c:" should have known",d:"will know"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:'Use "I should have known ___" to talk about something that you made a mistake about, but now you think that the correct answer is obvious.',examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:44,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1657,question:"He said, ' We shouldn't do it ........?",option:{a:"should we",b:"should be",c:" didn't we",d:"said he"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"He said, ' We shouldn't do it should we?",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:45,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1658,question:"After too much exercise, some people suffer from cramp which is caused by the ......... of the muscles",option:{a:"contraction",b:"restriction",c:"conscription",d:"relaxation"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that best complete the gap(s) 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:46,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1659,question:"'repri<u>e</u>ve''",option:{a:"rich",b:"police",c:"queer",d:"probity"},section:"For these questions, choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the ones represented by the letter (s) underlined",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`reprieve: /rɪˈpriːv/
police: /pəˈliːs/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:47,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1660,question:"'D<u>oo</u>r''",option:{a:"food",b:"cough",c:"sure",d:"board"},section:"For these questions, choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the ones represented by the letter (s) underlined",image:"",answer:"d",solution:`door: /dɔː/

board: /bɔːd/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:48,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1661,question:"'fam<u>ou</u>s''",option:{a:"soup",b:"cook",c:"pilot",d:"colonel"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that have same vowel sound as the ones represented by the letter (s) underlined
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`famous: /ˈfeɪməs/

pilot: /ˈpʌɪlət/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:49,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1662,question:"'<u>ch</u>oice''",option:{a:"schedule",b:"teach",c:"leisure",d:"machine"},section:"For these questions, choose the option that have the same consonant sound as the ones represented by the letter (s) underlined",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`choice: /tʃɔɪs/
teach: /tiːtʃ/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:50,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1663,question:"<u>y</u>et'''",option:{a:"bury",b:"way",c:"vessel",d:"europe"},section:"For these questions, choose the option that have the same consonant sound as the ones represented by the letter (s) underlined",image:"",answer:"d",solution:`yet: /jɛt/
europe: /ˈjʊr.əp/ `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:51,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1664,question:"task<u>ed</u>",option:{a:"bagged",b:"floored",c:"laughed",d:"shouted"},section:"For these questions, choose the option that have the same consonant sound as the ones represented by the letter (s) underlined",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`task; /tɑːskt/

laughed; /lɑːft/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:52,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1665,question:"Risen",option:{a:"prison",b:"motion",c:"portion",d:"rising"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that rhyme with the given words.
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`risen: rɪzən
prison: /ˈprɪz(ə)n/

 `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:53,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1666,question:"'terror''",option:{a:"tenor",b:"warrior",c:"error",d:"furrow"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that rhyme with the given words.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`terror: /ˈtɛrə/
error: /ˈɛrə/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:54,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1667,question:"crowd",option:{a:"crow",b:"bard",c:"aloud",d:"crawl"},section:`For these questions, choose the option that rhyme with the given words.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`crowd: /kraʊd/
aloud: /əˈlaʊd/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:55,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1668,question:"inoffensive",option:{a:"inOFfensive",b:"inoffenSIVE",c:"inofFENsive",d:"INoffensive"},section:"For these questions, choose the most appropriate stress pattern from the options. The Stressed syllable are written in capital letter (s)",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`Pronounced as in/of/FEN/sive.
The third syllable is more pronounced.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:56,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1669,question:"obligation",option:{a:"obliGAtion",b:"OBligation",c:"obligaTION",d:"obLIgation"},section:"For these questions, choose the most appropriate stress pattern from the options. The Stressed syllable are written in capital letter (s)",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"In nouns ending -isation or -ization, we stress the /eɪ/:",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:57,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1670,question:"disagreement",option:{a:"disAgreement",b:"disaGREEment",c:"DISagreement",d:"disagreeMENT"},section:"For these questions, choose the most appropriate stress pattern from the options. The Stressed syllable are written in capital letter (s)",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Primary syllable stress:   dis-a-gree-ment",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:58,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1671,question:"The car CRUSHED him.",option:{a:"Who did the car crush?",b:"Did a car crush him?",c:"What crushed him?",d:"Did the car injure him?"},section:"The words in capital letters have the emphatic stress. Choose the option to which the given sentence relates.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"In responding to questions on emphatic stress, Interrogative sentence that contradicts the emphasized word is the correct option. This means that, the statement that does not have the emphasized word in it is the correct answer. Option D is the correct answer here because the word ''injure contradicts crushed''.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:59,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1672,question:"Lamide is VERY hostile?",option:{a:"Is Lamide so hostile?",b:"Is Lamide friendly?",c:"Was Lamide very hostile?",d:"Who is hostile?"},section:"The words in capital letters have the emphatic stress. Choose the option to which the given sentence relates.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"In responding to questions on emphatic stress, Interrogative sentence that contradicts the emphasized word is the correct option. Option A is the correct answer here.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:60,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1673,question:"My house is a BUNGALOW",option:{a:" Is my house a terrace ?",b:"was my house a bungalow?",c:" Is my house the bungalow?",d:"Is his house a bungalow?"},section:"The words in capital letters have the emphatic stress. Choose the option to which the given sentence relates.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"To answer question on emphatic stress, the sentence that doesn't have the emphatic word becomes the correct answer. From the question, the emphatic stress is the word ''BUNGALOW''. only one option does not have bungalow in it which is option A",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016",questionNub:61,hasPassage:0,category:"others"}],a={subject:e,status:200,total:61,data:t};export{t as data,a as default,o as status,e as subject,s as total};
